There might be times when you want to combine
two datasets into one but with no logical way
or reason to join the two tables. You may want to
stack a list of records, one on top of the other.
To do this, we use a UNION keyword in between
two SELECT statements. Notice that column names
are not quite the same on each SELECT statement.
They don't need to be, but you will want to make
sure you line the data up so that one set of
records stacks neatly on top of the other.
I have this set to ORDER BY RecruitID, which
is a sort, and I will execute this query.
Notice that it would seem we have duplicates, but
we do not. Remember that this shows a combined
set of two recordsets, so there are bound to be
some duplicates among individual columns. Whereas
UNION stacks two recordsets into one output,
the INTERSECT keyword shows records that are
alike in both tables. I will change the keyword
from UNION to INTERSECT and execute the query.
It turns out that one person is in both
tables. To be considered an intersect,
each column in the query must have identical
values in both tables. The real-life application
here is that we would need to figure
out if this person is a recruit or not.